My keyboard has become a decoration.
Recently, I've been using voice input and AI together, to replace my keyboard.
In the last few months, I've dictated more than 130,000 English words,
and that's outside of work.
If you count all of the words I typed in using voice control,
that's probably twice as much as that.
AI being able to comprehend, understand what you mean exactly,
there is no need to type precisely.
You can basically use voice control to tell the rough ideas, the rough meaning, to AI,
and they can format the ideas in the perfect sense.
Let's take a real example.
This morning, I need to reply a Slack message.
Probably a few hundred words. In the past, it's going to take 15 to 20 minutes to reply.
But instead, I say these sentences to AI, via voice control:
'Help me reply to these Slack messages. Don't send anything. Just draft the message.
There are three things I want to deliver to the person.
First thing is, I agree that this is a true customer experience problem
that we need to prioritize to fix immediately.
The second thing is, I don't think we need a full analysis before we start fixing anything,
because out of these many problems, there are a few low-hanging fruit there
that we can pretty much start fixing straight away.
The third thing is, we should involve Bob Smith from the other team into this area,
because he has done recent analysis in this area.'
And that's it. 20 seconds later, there is a very well formatted message,
full of context, a lot of information pulled from previous conversations
injected into the message, delivered in three points, to my colleague.
So this is my two cents of how to use AI to increase your productivity,
to manage better in the age of AI.